[The Unclouded Soul]
[Episode 28]
Support Admin Watch on
kissasia.cam or kisskh.org
Don't be afraid, my son.
All of you are chipmunks?
Are you two demon-hunting immortals?
Our family has lived among humans
without harming anyone.
Please be merciful
and spare our lives.
I am Hong Ye, the Monarch of All Demons.
My duty
is to protect all demons.
-Greetings, Demon King.
I saw through your true forms last night.
But I noticed your son is confused,
unable to tell
whether he's human or demon.
Why has he become like this?
Also,
why aren't you properly cultivating
in the forest?
Instead, you mingle with humans,
deceiving them
and living dishonorably.
What's your purpose?
Please allow me to explain, Demon King.
Originally, our family of three
was, as you said,
peacefully cultivating in the mountains.
Ten years ago,
when my wife and I returned from foraging,
we found our home
invaded by humans.
They destroyed the mountains
and cut down trees.
Unfortunately, our power was too weak
to fight against them.
Not only was our home destroyed,
but our son was nowhere to be found.
But we firmly believed
that our son was still alive.
So,
we transformed into human form
and came to the human realm
to search for our son.
After many years of searching,
we finally found some clues.
It turned out our son
had been bought by a wealthy family.
Their young master
kept our son as a pet.
[Happiness]
We wanted to rescue our child,
but on their courtyard walls
were demon-repelling talismans
that prevented us from entering.
Therefore,
we could only wait nearby
for an opportunity.
Three years ago,
that family moved away.
Only then could we enter the courtyard
and find our son.
However,
at that time,
our son had lost his mind.
He not only failed to
recognize his parents
but considered that wealthy family
as his own.
He cried every day,
wanting to find his "family."
We tried many methods,
but our son refused to believe
he was a demon.
He insisted on finding that family.
We had no choice
but to frighten him
by saying his human parents
had been eaten by us.
And if he didn't obey,
we would eat him too.
Our son, in his confused state,
is attached to the human realm
and refuses to return to the mountains.
But in human territory,
money is a must.
Yes.
It was difficult for us
to raise him.
A couple of years ago,
a family took a liking to my son
and insisted on marrying
their daughter to him.
But we only found out after the marriage
that the girl already had a lover.
Her parents didn't approve of him,
so they used my son
to break up the couple.
We wanted to help the couple,
so we let the girl elope with her lover.
We gave her family a bloodstained garment
claiming she went to the mountains
to gather herbs
and was eaten by a demon.
The girl was grateful,
so she left her dowry with us.
So when you need money again,
you'll just find another marriage
for your son?
We only seek money,
not lives.
That girl, Cui,
was born to a concubine
of a wealthy family.
She was bullied
by her family since childhood
and had long wanted to leave
and make her own way.
We wanted money,
and she wanted freedom.
Though you're demons,
you place the blame
entirely on demons.
Unsolved human cases
are mostly blamed on demons.
One more or one less
doesn't make a difference.
Why do you only learn the bad things?
What do you plan to do in the future?
Originally, our family of three
lived freely cultivating in the mountains.
We only resent that the humans invaded,
destroyed our home,
and separated our family.
Now,
our home is no longer a home,
and we're neither human nor demon.
We live in constant fear every day,
afraid humans will discover we are demons.
For us two old ones,
our lives don't matter much.
We only fear that one day when we're gone,
our son will be left alone in this world,
struggling to survive.
[Happiness]
Thank you.
It seems we need to
resolve his trauma as soon as possible.
But my son's obsession runs too deep,
how can we resolve it?
Where did you find him?
Take us there.
Demon King.
This is the Xu Residence.
Tai!
Tai, I'm back!
Jin Jr.
You must be hungry.
Today my father punished me
with a day of fasting,
so you didn't get any food either.
These are rice grains
I picked up from under the table.
Between the two of us,
it can only fill one of us up.
You can have it all.
Today,
Squire Liu
brought his newly purchased bird
to show off to my father.
He said that bird
could speak human language
and cost him ten taels of gold.
In all of Tiansheng Kingdom,
there's only one like it.
I said,
"What's so great
about speaking human language?
My Jin Jr. can do that too."
With that,
Father slapped me across the face,
said I was lying,
and punished me with no food for a day
to teach me a lesson.
Jin Jr.
You need to show some spirit too.
Learn to speak human language
and put Squire Liu's bird in its place.
Jin Jr.
Have a candied chestnut.
Jin Jr., let me tell you,
these candied chestnuts
are the finest delicacy
in the human realm.
It's because my teacher gave me
the highest grade,
Mother agreed to buy these for me.
We are brothers.
From now on, if I have a bite,
you'll have a bite too.
From this day forward,
it will always be like this.
Here's another one for you.
My dad beats me every day.
I can't take it anymore.
Tonight,
let's run away from home together.
From now on,
no matter how far,
it'll just be us two brothers
traveling together.
What do you say?
You promised.
I knew it.
Even if everyone else abandons me,
I still have you as my brother.
Tai.
Why aren't you sleeping,
sitting on the wall
in the middle of the night?
Tai...
Where did you go?
Didn't we agree
that no matter how far,
we would travel together?
Demon King, look.
He still remembers the cage,
but doesn't know he's a chipmunk.
I'm afraid
we need to find his former playmate.
But the house
has been empty for three years.
How...
are we supposed to find them?
That's not difficult.
I have a way.
Wait here.
Sir,
how long has your shop been open?
This shop
was passed from my grandfather
to my father,
and then to me.
It's been three generations.
So that means
you know everything
about this town?
Of course.
I'd like to ask about something.
The residence across the street—
where did its owner go?
Why do you want to know?
We noticed the house is empty
and want to rent it to open an inn.
We'll be sure to support your business
when we do.
Sure.
The owner's surname is Xu.
He was originally the prefect of Dengzhou.
Due to political entanglements,
he was demoted and sent here.
After suffering for a few years,
he was reinstated
and returned to Dengzhou.
If you want to find him,
go to Dengzhou
and ask about Xu Residence.
Anyone will know.
Thank you.
Let's go to Dengzhou.
I seriously doubt your claim
that you've never left the palace
is true.
Why would I lie to you?
I have many more talents.
Let's go.
[Xu Residence]
Congratulations!
Thank you.
Please come in.
Please.
Congratulations!
Thank you.
Please come in.
Congratulations!
[50 taels of gift cash]
How festive!
Congratulations!
Congratulations.
Thank you.
Uncle Fu!
Is that really you?
I've finally found you.
Is Tai here?
My eyes aren't what they used to be.
May I ask your name, Sir?
I'm
Jin Jr.
Take a good look at me.
Jin...
Don't you...
remember me?
Uncle Fu,
I'm looking for Tai.
I've looked for him for three years.
Is he inside?
Sir, sir.
Please wait a moment.
Wu,
please look after him.
Sir.
Just a moment.
Young master,
there's a gentleman looking for you.
Who is it?
He knows my name
and claims to be an old friend of yours.
But I truly can't remember him.
This is the gentleman.
Tai.
Tai!
[Tai]
I've finally found you.
I missed you so much.
I missed you.
Sir.
Have you
mistaken me for someone else?
It's me, Jin Jr.
Don't you recognize me?
We used to hang out together every day.
We ate candied chestnuts
and climbed trees together.
Once you fell from a tree
and were bedridden for days.
And another time,
you wanted us to run away from home,
saying no matter how far,
we would travel together.
Sir,
I don't know
how you learned about
these childhood stories of mine.
But my father was very strict.
I grew up alone in our household
and never attended any private school.
I had no playmates,
let alone old friends.
I...
[Xu Residence]
Today is my wedding day.
You're welcome to stay
and have a drink
to share in our joy.
Uncle Fu,
please attend to our guest.
Yes.
Sir.
Please stay for a drink.
Have a drink.
Now that they've met,
he's experienced
the cold selfishness of humans.
His obsession will dissolve
and he'll return.
You have so little faith in humans?
Why don't we make another bet?
You lost the last round
and haven't paid your debt yet.
I found the bride first.
At best it was a tie.
Fine.
Let's make another bet then.
This time, let's bet that
true feelings won't be betrayed.
What's the stake?
Same as before.
You're back.
Yes.
You saw him?
It's good you saw him.
At least your wish is fulfilled.
From now on,
come home with us and live a good life.
Let's go.
All that talk about brotherhood
was just empty words.
In humans' eyes,
I'm just
a pet to pass their boring time.
It's over.
Don't think about it anymore.
Let's go.
Come.
Careful.
You wanted us to run away from home,
saying no matter how far,
we would travel together.
Tonight,
we'll escape from this house together.
From now on,
no matter how far,
it'll just be us two brothers
traveling together.
What do you say?
Jin Jr...
Jin Jr.
Your parents, for your sake,
lived in constant fear,
hiding among humans for the past decade,
risking their lives at every moment.
If they hadn't protected you
with all their might,
you wouldn't have survived till today.
These years of protection—
doesn't that deserve a thank you from you?
Dad and Mom,
I've put you in a difficult position.
Thank you.
All right,
let's not be so formal.
It's only natural
that we protect you.
You have such loving parents.
You should treasure them.
From now on,
the Princess will also be well protected.
Protected by whom?
Who?
Where?
If I truly had someone to rely on,
I might become quite spoiled.
That person better not regret it later.
If I am to be your protector,
I can handle it,
and I will excel at it.
Jin Jr.!
Quick, follow the young master.
Wait up, young master.
I remember now!
I haven't forgotten you, Jin Jr.!
I've always remembered you!
Jin Jr.!
Thank you!
For accompanying me through my youth.
The day I went home,
I opened the cage to set you free.
No matter how I tried to shoo you away,
you refused to leave.
My father wouldn't let me bring you.
I had no choice but to fill your cage
with nuts and chestnuts.
I hoped that after finishing them,
you would venture out
to find food yourself.
But I never expected
that after all these years,
you'd still be searching for me.
Jin Jr.,
you will always be my best brother!
No matter how far,
I am willing
to travel with you!
No matter how far,
I will never forget you.
Their ending was decided long ago.
The human and demon realms
living in peace
is the best ending for them.
So who wins this round?
You win.
Tell me,
what do you want me to do?
I haven't decided yet.
I'll tell you when I figure it out.
Take your time.
Jin Jr.
Do you have any attachments left?
My wish has been fulfilled.
In this life,
I only wish to serve my parents.
If that's the case,
shall I take you to Demons' Valley?
Demons' Valley?
The legendary Demons' Valley?
Does such a place really exist?
You'll find out when you get there.
The mountains and lakes here
are all protected by barriers.
Humans aren't able to find this place.
Demons from all regions
have gathered here
and live in peace with each other.
You can find a quiet place
for your cultivation.
If you need anything,
come find me at Youning Cave.
Thank you, Demon King.
Let's go.
Ning'an.
A hundred years ago...
Except for those two bridges,
nothing changed here.
Your development is too slow.
You recognize them?
The Zhuyu herb.
You know quite a lot.
They are spirit herbs from Mount Zhaoyao
that have achieved cultivation.
These spirit herbs
have miraculous effects.
If humans eat them,
they can go without food for seven days.
That's why in human territories,
they've been eaten almost to extinction.
Fortunately, the Demon King was generous
and helped relocate them
to Demons' Valley,
allowing them to survive until today.
Am I right, My Lord?
How did you know all this?
From my dreams.
Tell me,
how many times have you dreamed about me?
Many times.
For a demon, the path of cultivation
is exceptionally difficult.
One must possess innate wisdom,
draw upon the essence
of heaven and earth,
follow the laws of nature's cycles,
and endure countless seasons and moons—
only then may one take human form.
Meanwhile,
they must also evade pursuit
from both humans and their own kind.
How do bamboos fare here?
Bamboos?
Yes.
Didn't you say
all things possess innate wisdom
and can achieve human form?
I have lived for thousands of years,
but have never seen a bamboo
successfully cultivate.
So you're the first
bamboo to achieve human form.
No wonder you're so proud.
Cultivation is difficult,
so I'll be generous
and not eat you.
Those three
were mythical beasts from ancient times.
They died in the war against humans.
To commemorate them,
the demons carved
their images on the mountain.
Teng She, Ao Hen, and Qiong Qi.
Is there anything else you haven't seen?
Yes,
quite a lot.
Take me to meet your demon subjects.
Bi Fang
is shaped like a crane
with a single foot;
it has a red-patterned teal body
-with a white beak.
-Through the water curtain
is the Demons' Valley Academy.
-It's called...
-It's called the Moon-Gazing Terrace.
Bi Fang.
Its call is its own name.
Who among you knows
what Bi Fang's true form is?
Xiao Yao,
you answer.
Wait, wait.
Sir, let me think.
It looks like a crane with one foot.
It looks like a crane with one foot!
And...
Wait a moment, wait a moment.
Delicious.
Wait, wait.
What's going on? I can't find it.
Dali!
-Wait.
-Red-patterned teal body with white beak.
Red—
If there's a next time,
I will banish you
from Moon-Gazing Terrace.
Recite it 30 times together,
then I'll continue the lesson.
I used to hate the Master's nagging,
but after being away
from class for so long,
I actually miss it.
The academy in Demons' Valley
is quite different from those of humans.
Quickly raise the water curtain
and take me closer for a look.
Then stay behind me
and don't let them discover you're human.
I'm a little snake.
I just shed my skin.
His Lordship discovered me
and brought me back to Demons' Valley
to learn demon knowledge.
My Lord,
have you forgotten?
No.
Do you understand?
My Lord.
Greetings, My Lord.
This is the academy's teacher,
King of Eight Plates.
Hello, Sir.
I really want to hear your lessons again.
I promise I won't get distracted
or daydream anymore.
If you want to learn,
you can start anytime.
Having a student like you
makes me very pleased.
This is her first time
in Demons' Valley today.
I'll show her around first.
Please continue with your class.
Your coming to Demons' Valley
is as if you're returning home—
you're familiar with everything.
Where did this come from?
I weaved it for fun.
Xiao Ming.
Don't be rude.
Don't be afraid.
He's a little cat I adopted.
Okay.
Xiao Ming.
Let me ask her first.
Who are you?
She...
She wandered in the human realm
for many years
and I just happened to find her.
Are you a demon too?
I'm a little snake.
That's right.
Then where are your scales?
I shed them.
Shed?
Yeah.
Snakes eat mice.
Eat one to prove it to me.
Why should I?
That's not necessary.
But...
But My Lord, her scent is strange.
What scent could she possibly have?
Are you always this rude?
When was I ever rude?
-My Lord.
-You're the one who's odd.
Do you see...
Back up.
Don't be afraid.
Come.
Okay.
This is where
I usually cultivate.
You can rest here for now.
Let me tell you something.
You'd better not make me angry.
My Lord.
Xiao Mu.
Why are you being so disrespectful today?
My Lord.
I...
Xiao Mu.
Let me have a close look at her.
My Lord.
Xiao Mu is actually looking out
for your best interests.
You've been away from Demons' Valley
for so long.
Heiwu has been spreading rumors
about you everywhere,
saying your going to the human realm
to search for demon treasures
is just an excuse.
The truth is, you have
an intimate relationship with humans,
and that you keep showing goodwill
to humans.
It's been making everyone anxious.
We just hope
that you'll be more careful.
Don't give him any ammunition against you.
Huh?
Heiwu has been like that
since centuries ago?
-You know Heiwu?
He's a nightmare.
Never mind about nightmares.
Humans are hunting demons everywhere now.
Heiwu led some demons
and killed quite a few humans too.
Just now
he brought a pile of "trophies."
Now he's in front
of the elders at Youning Cave
seeking credit for his deeds.
Whenever he gets a chance,
he tries to discredit you.
What we mean is,
since you've returned, My Lord,
you should quickly go to Youning Cave
and show yourself
to prove your innocence.
Why didn't you say that earlier?
What do you mean?
-I've said so much—
-Forget it.
I happen to have important matters
to discuss with the elders.
I shall meet with Heiwu while I'm there.
Yes.
Wait for me here.
Don't wander off.
Not every demon
in Demons' Valley is friendly.
Xiao Ming.
Take good care of Ning'an.
Wait for my return.
Okay.
Don't worry, My Lord.
I'll keep a close eye on her.
I'll watch her.
I'll take care of her.
My Lord!
Don't worry, it's fine.
This is for you.
It's a welcome gift.
Hey!
Let me tell you.
Don't try to fool me with things
that only work on minor demons.
You're clearly cunning.
Acting all sweet in front of His Lordship.
I can see right through you.
You can be really annoying sometimes.
I...
But
you're also the most loyal
and devoted to His Lordship
among all demons.
So
I do like you a little bit.
Of course.
Let me tell you,
in the whole of Demons' Valley,
when it comes to loyalty to His Lordship,
I, Xiao Ming, rank first,
and Xiao Mu only dares to rank second.
If you don't believe me,
I'll let Xiao Mu come out and tell you.
No, no.
Don't fight.
I believe you.
Why do you share one body?
Which one of you is older
and which is younger?
I'm not quite sure about that either.
All I know is that
including us,
we were nine siblings.
We all cultivated together originally.
But by the end,
only Xiao Mu and I remained.
And before we achieved human form,
we went through
a major heavenly tribulation.
Xiao Mu lost his life protecting me.
I barely managed to catch Xiao Mu's soul
to share my body with him.
But as you know,
having two souls in one body
always causes power disturbances.
We nearly lost our lives.
Fortunately, His Lordship appeared in time
and brought us back to Demons' Valley.
He taught us methods of cultivation,
allowing us to stabilize our minds
up until today.
So ever since then,
Xiao Ming is Xiao Mu,
and Xiao Mu is Xiao Ming.
We are inseparable.
No wonder you're so loyal and devoted.
Of course.
Have a seat.
But there's one thing
I must admit.
The truth is,
Xiao Mu and I had very weak powers.
And
Xiao Mu can be quite sharp-tongued.
So many great demons
disliked us both
and bullied us constantly.
Only His Lordship
never abandoned us
and treated us with such favor.
So since then,
Xiao Mu and I decided
to cultivate day and night
to make our powers stronger,
even stronger.
Only this way
can we be helpful to His Lordship
and not bring him shame.
You are His Lordship's best companions.
One day,
when His Lordship faces hardships,
only you will protect him.
Are you serious?
It's His Lordship.
No one among demons
or humans is his match.
How could it possibly
be our turn to protect him?
That's right.
I hope that day never comes.
Duh.
Elders, you have to believe me.
This is exactly what Hong Ye is like.
My Lord has returned.
My Lord, who has been working tirelessly
for the demons,
has finally returned.
This time,
what sacred demon relic have you
brought back for us?